Williams Umogbai

Teacher

Contact

Address

Port Harcourt, Nigeria, 500272

Phone

08065238432

E-mail

wagbarafranklin1@gmail.co m

Skills

Group learning mechanics

Excellent

Student-centered learning

Excellent

Classroom management

Excellent

Blackboard software

Excellent

Inquiry-based learning

Excellent

Differentiated instruction

Excellent

Languages

English Language

Compassionate, creative and effective Teacher with valuable experience in classroom administration, professional development and project planning. Equipped with extensive background in versatile education environments. Student-centric instructor, academic facilitator and motivational coach. Competent at performing independently or as member of teaching team. Well-versed in classroom and online technologies.

Work History

2012-04 -Current

Teacher

Brookstone School, Port Harcourt, Rivers State

- Communicated frequently with parents, students and faculty to provide feedback and discuss instructional strategies.
- Planned and implemented integrated lessons to meet national standards.
- Evaluated and revised lesson plans and course content to achieve student-centered learning.
- Incorporated exciting and engaging activities to achieve student participation and hands-on learning.
- Developed and implemented lesson plans that addressed general students as well as those with individualized 504 plans as part of integrated classroom.
- Completed daily reports on attendance and disciplinary performance.
- Graded and evaluated student assignments, papers and course work.

2007-09 -2012-04

Teacher

Graceland, Port Harcourt, Rivers State

- Planned and implemented integrated lessons to meet national standards.
- Communicated frequently with parents, students and faculty to provide feedback and discuss instructional strategies.
- Incorporated multiple types of teaching strategies into classroom.
- Instructed students in core educational principles,

Excellent

Etsako(Ekperi) Language

Excellent

concepts and in-depth subject matter.

- Reviewed curriculum and devised alternate approaches to presenting lessons to increase student understanding.
- Graded and evaluated student assignments, papers and course work.
- Designed dynamic lesson plans based on student interests to increase overall student GPA.
- Collaborated with faculty to develop after-school tutoring program for struggling students.

2004-11 -2007-08

Vice Principal Academics

Babanawa College, Ikeje, Kogi

- Supervision of Teaching and Learning Programmes
- Supervise and co-ordinate all the academic affairs
 of the school and ensure a high level of excellence
 as regards the school's academic activities on a
 daily basis.
- Supervise the Academic schedules of duties of the Supervisor and the Registrar as it relates to academic matters.
- Ensure the compliance of learners and academic staff to rules and regulations pertaining to curricular and co-curricular activities.
- Liaise with the Vice Principal (Admin.) where appropriate.
- Oversees the Academic Programme of the college and reports lapses (weaknesses) to the principal.
- Does regular and formal classroom visits.

2001-02 -2004-11

Principal

Life Line College, Fugar, Edo

- Supervision of Teaching and Learning Programme.
- Oversee the implementation of the Electronic Learning Strategy on ICT development and learning.
- Supervise and co-ordinate all the academic affairs
 of the school and ensure a high level of excellence
 as regards the school's academic activities on a
 daily basis.
- Liaise with the Vice Principal where appropriate.
- Ensures that the academic standard of the College is of the highest quality and excellence.

- Manage Internal and International Examinations and Tests.
- Supervise educational programs designed for the school, evaluating Diction Programme of Learners and Educators observing classes on a regular basis.

Education

1997-07 - 2000-12	Bachelor of Arts: History And International Studies
	Ambrose Alli University - Epkoma, Edo State
1984-09 - 1988-12	High School Diploma
	Momodu - Agbede, Edo State

Accomplishments

 Led Year 9, 11, 12 to excellent performances in IGCSE, WAEC, NECO examinations.

Certifications

2011-01	Educational Management and Administration Programme
2015-08	Coaching, Mentoring and Counselling Training
2012-06	Core Subjects of The Current Curriculum
2017-08	Leadership, Teaching, Child Psychology Training Certification

Interests

Reading and Writing

Researching and Teaching

Personal Information

State of Origin - Edo State

LGA of Origin - Etsako-Central Date of Birth - 3rd March, 1968 Marital Status - Married